A Finding Aid to the Tomás Ybarra-Frausto Research Material on Chicano Art, 1965-2004, in the Archives of American Art AAA.ybartoma
Archives of American Art
- Subject Files, 1965-1997; Series 1
  - Chicano Art: Resistance and Affirmation continued (Box 7)
    - Planning - NEH Proposal, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 4)
      (letter to TYF from Holly Barnet-Sanchez, 07/12/1989; copy of proposal submitted to the NEH on 06/09/1989)
    - San Antonio (see also: Compañeras; La Peña Cultural Arts Center), 1993 (Box 7, Folder 5)
      (performance announcement - unrelated to CARA?; invitation to exhibition opening; clippings, one related to Compañeras exhibit; CARA newsprint flyer)
    - San Francisco, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 6)
      (invitation; publicity packet; clippings; symposium announcement/abstrace/schedule; invitations)
    - TYF's Contributions, 1989-1990 (Box 7, Folder 7)
      (letter to TYF from Holly Barnet Sanchez and Marcos Sanchez-Tranquilino, 04/26/1989, re. TYF's contract for his essay; correspondence re. TYF's loan for the exhibition, 1990, and receipts; TYF's notes for his essay for the catalog)
    - Washington D.C., 1992-1993 (Box 7, Folder 8)
      (clippings; invitation to exhibition opening; program of events; National Museum of American Art May and June 1992 schedules brochure; NMAA symposium "Contemporary Mexican-American Culture" - notification and invitation; press release)
  - Chicano Art Resources Information Development and Dissemination (CARIDAD), Organization, University of California at Santa Barbara (see also Galeria de la Raza/Studio 24), 1991; (booklet, Chicano Art: A Resource Guide) (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Chicano Arts from the Border States of the U.S., Exhibition, Cornerhouse, Manchester, England, 1993; (postcards of art from the exhibition) (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Chicano Cinema (see also: Noriega, Chon), 1990 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    ("Chicano Cinema: Una Poca De Gracia"; course packet for UGS043, Winter Quarter)
  - Chicano Cultural Conference, Conference, Paris, France (see also: Menández, Nina), 1986 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    (postcard to TYF from Nina Menández)
  - Chicano Culture, undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
    (course-related materials [?]; outline; poems; Zoot suit handouts)
  - The Chicano Experience: John Hernandez, Benito Huerta, Exhibition, InterAmerican Art Gallery, Miami-Dade Community College, Miami, Florida, 1988; (catalog) (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Chicano Expressions: A New View in American Art (see also: Border Art; INTAR), 1986 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    (exhibition, Intar Latin American Gallery, New York and El Centro Chicano, Stanford University; catalog; exhibition announcement; activity schedule)
  - Chicano! History of the Mexican American Civil Rights Movement, Project, National Latino Communications Center, 1993; (publication; informational packet) (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Chicano Humanities and Arts Council (CHAC), Denver, Colorado (Box 7)
    - Black Velvet Painting, 1991-1993 (Box 7, Folder 17)
      (letter to TYF from Jennifer Heath, CHAC, 01/29/1993; clippings)
    - CHAC Reporter, 1981-1993 (Box 7, Folder 18)
      (newsletter: 12/81; 03/82; 05/82; 06-07/82; 08-09/82; 10-11/82; 01/83; 02-03/83; 04-05/83; 08-09/83; 10-11/83; 01-02/84; 03-04/84; 05-06/84; 07-08/84; 09-10/84; 11-12/84; 03-04/85; 05-06/85; 06-07/85; 07/85; 08/85; 09/85; 10-11/85; 12/85; 01/86; 02/86; 03/86; 04/86; 05/86; 06/86; 07/86; 08/86; 09/86; 10/86; 01/8702/87; 04/92; 01/93)
    - General, 1981-1992 (Box 7, Folder 19)
      (Raices y Razones - Roots and Reasons: Symbolism in Chicano Art; presentation summary; poster; Amor en Aztlán Acrosscultural fiesta: announcement and calendar of events; CHAC design contest entry form; exhibition announcements; organization brochures; invitations; event announcements; CHAC Center User Survey, blank; photocopy of floor plan for Denver facility; clippings)
  - Chicano/Latino Archive, The Evergreen State College Library, Olympia, Washington, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    ("Guide to the Chicano/Latino Archive")
  - Chicano Life and Culture Class, undated; (graphs, charts and tables) (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Chicano Literature, 1981-1983; (bibliography; brochure; clippings) (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Chicano Movement, undated (Box 7, Folder 23)
    ( The Chicano Movement: Some Not Too Objective Observations By Abelardo B. Delgado, Denver: Colorado Migrant Council; distributed by Totinem Publications, 1971; essays by TYF, Richard A. Garcia, Tomás Almaguer "The Chicano Movement and the Emergence of a Chicano Poetic Consciousness"; "The Chicano Movement and the Mexican American Community, 1972-1978: An Interpretive Essay"; "Chicano Politics in the Present Period: Comment on Garcia")
  - Chicano Narrative and Literary Criticism, undated; (conference schedule) (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Chicano Now: American Expressions, Exhibition, Alameda Museo Americano, San Antonio, Texas (see also: Chicano Visions: American Painters on the Verge), 2001-2002 (Box 7, Folder 25)
    (brochures; invitation; unused temporary tattoo)
  - Chicano Park, San Diego, California, 1973-1989 (Box 7, Folder 26)
    (film; clippings; essay, "The Story of Chicano Park" by Eva Cockroft)
  - Chicano Park, 1987-1989, undated (Box 7, Folder 27)
    (film; flyer; information sheets about the film and its background including synopsis; photocopies of drawings made by elementary school students in response to the film and letter to producers from their teacher, 06/12/1987; photocopies of letters to the producers from: Gregroio Cervantes, Inland Counties Legal Services, 05/19/1989; Manuel Gomez, Assistant Vice Chancellor, Academic Affairs, U.C. Irvine, 04/06/1989; Francisco H. Vázquez, Director, World Studies Program, World College West, 06/07/1989; Laura Rodriguez, one of the people in the film, undated; J. Hunter Todd, Chairman and Founder, Houston International Film Festival; Susan Adkisson, Administrative Assistant, Mexican American Commission, State of Nebraska, 04/18/1989; invitation/program for San Francisco premier of the film)
  - Chicano Photographers, 1985-circa 1998; (see also: En Foco, Inc.; photography; Box 30) (Box 7, Folder 28)
    ( Nueva Luz: A Photographic Journal, vol.4, no.2, 1993; booklet; clipping)
  - Chicano Studies, Course, 1983; (course information, syllabus, etc.) (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Chicano Studies - Bound Volume, 1983; (course readings) (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Chicano Secret Service, Humor Troupe, 1992; (performance announcement) (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Chicano Visions: American Painters on the Verge, Exhibition, San Antonio Museum of Art (see also: Chicano Now), 2002-2004; (clippings; exhibition brochure; Museum of Contemporary Art, San Diego, museum bulletin) (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Chicanos Gráficos...California, Exhibition, Southern California State College, undated; (catalog) (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Chicolandia, Exhibition, Movimiento Artistico de Rio Salado, Phoenix, Arizona (see also: Movimiento Artistico del Rio Salado - MARS; photography), 1993; (exhibition announcement) (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Chismearte, Journal, Concilio de Arte Popular, Los Angeles, California, XhismeArte (Box 7, Folder 35-37)
    (Fall 1976, no.1; Winter/Spring 1977, no. 2; Vol.1, no.3 1977; Special Issue 1977; vol. 2, no.1 1978; Feb. 1980; No. 7, Jan. 1981 - Special Woman's Issue; No. 9, 1983; No. 10, May 1984)
  - Chispas, 1983-1984 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    (magazine, funded by Movimiento Estudiantil Chicano de Aztlan - M.E.Ch.A., University of California, Berkeley. Vol. 12, no.2, Spring 1983; Vol. 13, no.1, Fall 1983; Vol. 13, no.2, Spring 1984; U.C. Berkeley Chicano Studies Program information sheet)
  - ¡Chispas! Cultural Warriors of New Mexico, Exhibition, Heard Museum, Phoenix, Arizona, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    (catalog, ¡Chispas! Cultural Warriors of New Mexico, Phoenix, Arizona: The Heard Museum, 1993)
  - Cholo Art, 1999, undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
    (poem; mazagine, Vida Loca: A Magazine by Raza and for La Raza, no. 69, May/June 1999)
  - Cholos (see also: Low Riders) (Box 8)
    - Cholo Art: Brown Pride, Magazine, vol. 1 no. 1, April 1981 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Cholismo (see also: José Cuellar), 1980-85 (Box 8, Folder 5)
      (typescripts of papers: "Lowriding: The Fusion of Cultural Symbols and the Diffusion of Cultural Myths", presented at the Nation Association for Chicano Studies Conference, Houston, 04/1981; "The Rise and Spread of Cholismo as a Border Youth Subculture", prepared for the Southwest Border Regional Conference's Third Annual Binational Border Governors' Conference, Tijuana, 09/1982; draft of project report on the project, "Cultural Change and Continuity Among Borderland Youth: The Signs and Symbols of Cholismo on the Frontera; clippings)
    - Cholografiá Photographs, circa 1983-1984; (publications list; clipping; photographs of low-rider cars; poem) (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - General, 1980-1986, undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
      (publication announcements; clippings; newsletter, El Grito/The Call, CET, undated)
    - Iconography (see also: Cuellar, José), undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
      (lecture announcements: "Cholo Iconography")
    - Low Rider Magazine ( Arte del Varrio), 1979-1982, 1984; (see also Box 30) (Box 8, Folder 9)
      (no.1, 1979, sol; May 1979; no. 2, 1980, sol; January 1981; March 1981; Spring 1981; June 1981; 1982; March 1984; Vivo Magazine, vol. 1, no. 3, 1982)
    - Reading of Lifestyle, 1981, 1989, undated (Box 8, Folder 10)
      (TYF's notes on Low Riders, or cholos; essays; clippings)
    - Varrio San José: Scenes from an Urban Chicano Experience, Exhibition, National Museum of American History, Smithsonian Institution, Washington, D.C. (see also: Photography), 1990; (catalog) (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Cid, Armando Ramirez, 1973-1983; (clippings; exhibition announcement) (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Cinco de Mayo (see also: Mesa-Bains, Amalia), 1981-1987, undated (Box 8, Folder 13)
    ( Cinco de Mayo: A Resource Handbook, San Francisco Unified School District - curriculum booklet; clippings; TYF's notes on history of 5 de Mayo)
  - Cinco Pintoras, Exhibition, 516 University Art Museum Downtown, University of New Mexico, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1996; (exhibition announcement; clippings) (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Cisneros, J. George, 1981, 1999; (catalog; ArtPace International Artist-In-Residence Program artist brochure) (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Cisnereos, José, Artist (1910 -), 1977-2004 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    (clippings; Southwestern Studies monograph, Faces of the Borderlands: Twenty-one Drawings by José Cisneros, with text by the artist, Texas Western Press, University of Texas at El Paso, El Paso, Texas)
  - Cisneros, Timothy, 1974; (clipping) (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Cockroft, Eva (see: Chicano Park) (Box 8)
  - Cofradía de Artes y Artesanos Hispánicos, New Mexico, 1979; (clipping) (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - El Colegio de la Frontera Norte, Tijuana, Baja California, Mexico, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    (announcement of presentation to be made by TYF)
  - Colón, Miriam, 1981; (clipping) (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Colorado (see also: Sandoval, Carlos), 1972-1994; (2 folders) (Box 8, Folder 21-22)
    (clippings; TYF's notes; catalogs; Colorado Springs Fine Ars Center Publication List; exhibition announcements; brochures)
  - Colorado La Cucaracha (see also: Lucero, Stephen P.), 1982-1983 (Box 8, Folder 23)
    (magazine published by El Periodico La Cucaracha, Inc., Pueblo, Colorado; 20 de Febrero, 1982, vol. 7, no. 2; 17 de Marzo, 1982, vol. 7, no. 3; 14 de Abril, 1982, vol. 7, no.4; 11 de Junio, 1982, vol. 7, no. 6; 14 de Agosto, 1982, vol. 7, no. 8; 23 de Octubre, 1982, vol. 7, no. 10; 27 de Noviembre, 1982, vol. 7, no.11; 22 de Diciembre, 1982, vol. 7, no. 12; 21 de Enero, 1983, vol. 8, no. 1; 18 de Febrero, 1983, vol. 8, no. 2; 28 de Marzo, 1983, vol. 8, no. 3)
  - Colorado - Notes, undated; (list of articles and their locations) (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Colorado - La Voz, Magazine, 1982-83; (see Box 31) (Box 8, Folder 25)
    (29 de diciembre, 1982, vol. 8, no. 52; 2 de marzo, 1983, vol. 9, no. 9; 9 de marzo, 1983, vol. 9, no. 10; 16 de marzo, 1983, vol. 9, no. 11; 23 de marzo, 1983, vol. 9, no. 12)
  - Colorado, Hortensia, Actress, Resume, undated (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Comité Mexicano Cívico Patriótico, San Francisco, California, 1987; (invitation) (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Community and Contemporary Chicano Art: Four El Paso Artists, 2000; (instructional resource; photocopy) (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Community Murals, Magazine, International Community Muralists' Network (see also: SPARC), 1984-1989 (Box 8, Folder 29)
    (letter to TYF from Eva, Social and Public Art Resource Center (SPARC), 11/17/1989, re. Community Murals; Spring 1984; Winter 1985, vol. 10, no. 1; Spring 1987, vol. 12, no. 1; Summer 1987, vol. 12, no. 2; Fall 1987, vol. 12, no. 3; Winter 1987, vol. 12, no. 4)
  - Compañeras Exhibition, Austin, Texas (see also Barraza, Santa), 1993-1996; (exhibition announcements; clippings) (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Comprehensive Employment Training Act (CETA) Artist Program, undated; (clipping) (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - La Comunidad, 1983, 1987; (see: Box 31) (Box 8, Folder 32)
    (newspaper: Sunday supplement to The Opinion, Los Angeles, California. 27 de marzo, 1983; 3 de abril, 1983; 5 de junio, 1983; 10 de julio, 1983; 14 de agosto, 1983; 11 de septiembre, 1983; 10 de mayo, 1987)
  - Con Safo Group, San Antonio, Texas, Organization (see also: Casas, Mel; Martinez, Santos; Reyes, Felipe), 1971-2000, undated (Box 8, Folder 33)
    (letter to Dr. Guy Bensusan, Associate Professor, University of Arizona, 07/22/1972; Con Safo organizational information: list of needs, meeting notes, mission statement - Brown Paper Report; "General Comments" [by Felipe Reyes?]; clippings; exhibition announcements; catalogs; photographs of Con Safo members; material for TYF's course on Chicano Culture)
  - "Con Safo: The San Antonio Chicano Group and Its Legacy,", circa 1999-2000 (Box 8, Folder 34)
    (multiple drafts of paper by Ruben Cordova)
  - Con Safos, Publication of the Organization Con Safo, Los Angeles, California, 1968, 1969, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Concha, Jerry, circa 1975; (resume) (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - Concilio de Arte Popular, State Coalition of La Raza Artists, California, Organization (see also: ChismeArte; XhismeArte), 1977-1979, undated (Box 8, Folder 37)
    (board meeting minutes; meeting announcement; Chicano Artistas "Priciples of Organization"; member address list)
  - Concilio Mujeres, 1983, undated (Box 8, Folder 38)
    (organization, San Francisco, California, founded by La Raza women; organizational information; invitation)
  - Concreto/Concrete, Newsletter, College of Environmental Design, University of California at Berkeley, 21-28 November 1978, 16 May 1979 (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - Congreso de Artistas Chicanos en Aztlán, Exhibition, San Diego, California, circa 1974; (exhibition announcement) (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - Connections in Chicano and Latino Art, Center for the Arts, Exhibition, San Francisco, California, 1991; (exhibition announcements) (Box 8, Folder 41)
  - Conquest - Consequences, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 42)
    (exhibition: 1598, 1848, 1898: Conquest and Consequences, Museo de las Américas, Denver, Colorado, catalog)
  - Contact II, Poetry Review, Vol. 6, no. 34/35 Winter/Spring, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 43)
  - Contemporary Chicana and Chicano Art, Book, Bilingual Press, Hispanic Research Center, Arizona State University, Tempe, Arizona, 2000 (Box 8, Folder 44)
    (invitation to Chicana/o or Latina/o Artists to participate in the book)
  - Contemporary Hispanic Shrines, Exhibition, Freedman Gallery, Albright College, Reading, Pennsylvania, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 45)
    (catalog, Contemporary Hispanic Shrines, Freedman Gallery, Albright College, Reading, Pennsylvania)
  - Contemporary Hispanic Women Artists of Texas, Exhibition, 1990; (catalog) (Box 8, Folder 46)
  - Contreras, Rodolfo, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 47)
    (note to TYF from Contreras, circa 12/93)
  - Corazón de Aztlán, Exhibition, Oakes College, University of California at Santa Cruz, 1981; (information packet; poster, moved to Sol; see also: Box 30) (Box 8, Folder 48)
  - Cornell University, Revelaciones/Revelations, Exhibitions, 1993; (exhibition announcements; calendar of events; clipping) (Box 8, Folder 49)
  - Coronado Studio, 2003 (Box 8, Folder 50)
    (Serie Print Project, organization; organization brochure; exhibition announcement; CD with images from Serie I-VIII, '93/'94 - '00-'01)
  - Corona, Juan - Court Case, circa 1981; (clipping) (Box 8, Folder 51)
  - Corpus Delecti, Exhibition/Performance/Conference on Latino Performance Art, Institute of Contemporary Art, London, undated; (press release) (Box 8, Folder 52)
  - Cortéz, Carlos (see also: Moviemient Artistico Chicano), 1981-1983, undated (Box 8, Folder 53)
    (poetry booklets; letter to members from Cortez; clipping; list of artists)
  - Corzas, Francisco, 1983; (clipping) (Box 8, Folder 54)
  - Counter Colón-Ialismo (see also: Movimento Artistico del Rio Salado (MARS), 1993, undated (Box 8, Folder 55)
    (exhibition, Centro Cultural de la Raza, San Diego, California; Mexi-Arte, Austin, Texas, and MARS, Phoenix, Arizona; exhibition announcement; invitation)
  - Covarrubias, Miguel, undated (Box 8, Folder 56)
    (TYF's notes on Covarrubias)
  - Crocker Art Museum, Sacramento, California, 1983-1991; (calendars of exhibitions, lectures and other events; catalog; press releases) (Box 8, Folder 57)
  - Crossing Borders: U.S. Latina/o Queer Performance, Conference, Austin, Texas: the Center for Lesbian & Gay Studies of the City University of New York; the Center for Dramatic & Performance Studies of the University of Texas-Austin, 2001; (conference announcement) (Box 8, Folder 58)
  - Cruzando Fronteras, Conference, El Colegio de la Frontera Norte (COLEF), Tijuana, Baja California, Mexico, 1991; (field report) (Box 8, Folder 59)
  - Cuatro: Form and Light in Cyberspace, Multi-media installation, California Museum of Photography, University of California, Riverside (see also Gamboa, Harry Jr.), 2001; (clipping) (Box 8, Folder 60)
  - Cuauhtemoc: Homenaje y Celebración, (Dance Celebration Sponsored by Danza Xitlalli Dance Troupe), 1989; (announcement) (Box 8, Folder 61)
  - La Cucaracha (see: Colorado; and Lucero, Stephen P.), (newspaper/magazine) (Box 8)
  - Cuellar, José B., 1975; (resume) (Box 8, Folder 62)
  - Cuevas, José Luis, 1975; (clipping) (Box 8, Folder 63)
  - Cultura Popular (see also: Flores, Juan; Popular Culture), undated; (clippings/course readings; syllabus; essays by Juan Flores) (Box 8, Folder 64)
  - Cultural Refractions, Exhibition, Cultural Refractions: Border Life en la tierra de nadie, Galería Sin Fronteras, Austin, Texas (see also: Border Art; Border Culture; Photography), 1998 (Box 8, Folder 65)
  - Culture Clash, Collaborative Group, San Francisco, California, 1990-1999; (clipping; exhibition announcements) (Box 8, Folder 66)
  - Curare: Espacio Critíco para las Artes, Workshop, Mexico City, Mexico, 1992; (brochure; leaflets; exhibition announcement) (Box 8, Folder 67)
  - Cut/Across, Exhibition, Washington Project for The Arts, Washington, D.C. Catalog, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 68)
  - Dále Gas: Chicano Art of Texas, Exhibition, Contemporary Arts Museum, Houston, Texas (see also: Burciaga, José Antonio; Casas, Mel; De León, Nephtalí; Martínez, Santos; Mora, Jo; Treviño, Jesus), 1977 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    (catalog signed by Carmen Lomas-Garza; exhibition checklist)
  - Dále Kranque -- Chicano Music and Art in Southern Texas (see also: Martínez, César), circa 1982 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    (collection of essays on Chicano music and art with biographies of musicians and artists, Dále Kranque: Chicano Music and Art in South Texas, Chicano Music and Art Project, University of Minnesota)
  - Dávila, Atanasio P., Painter (1909-), 1980; (clipping) (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Day of the Dead (see: Día de los Muertos) (Box 9)
  - de la Campa, Román, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    (essay reprint, "Latin Lessons: Do Latinos Share a World... Or Word?" Oxford UP, 1994)
  - de la Riva, Dolores (Lola; see also: Carillo, Eduardo), 1971-1986, undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
    (research progress report; Faculty Mentor Program forms and paperwork; clippings; note to TYF from de la Riva, undated)
  - de la Torre, Einar and Jamex, 1991-2003 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    (clippings; resume; typescript sections and drafts of catalogs; catalogs; catalog, Crossing Boundaries: Jamex and Einar de la Torre, Steven La Ponsie, and Ronald Gonzalez, Fisher Gallery, University of Southern California, University Park, Los Angeles, 1999)
  - de la Rocha, Roberto (see: Los Four) (Box 9)
  - de León, Alex, 1988-1995, undated; (clippings; exhibition announcement; ArtPace International Artist-In-Residence Program brochure) (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - De León, Nephtalí, Poet, Painter, Writer (1945-), 1984 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    (correspondence re. de León's daughter's illness; flyer listing de León's accomplishments and activites; auction announcement and clippings related to de León's mural "El Molcajete Cósmico")
  - De Mujer A Mujer: A Celebration of Latinas by Latina Artists, Exhibition, Austin Museum of Art, Austin, Texas, 1996-1997; (gallery guide; exhibition checklist; exhibition announcements) (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - De Soto, Ernesto F., Master printer, undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - de Soto, Lewis, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    (ArtPace International Artist-In-Residence Program artist biography brochure)
  - Delano, Irene, Artist, 1919-1982, 1988; (catalog) (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Delano, Jack, Photographer, 1914-1997, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    (catalog, Contrasts: Forty Years of Change and Continuity in Puerto Rico, Smithsonian Institution Traveling Exhibition Service, 1990)
  - Delgado Ríos, Roberto, 1982, 1988, undated; (clippings; exhibition announcement) (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Denver Youth Conference, Denver, Colorado, 1970; (clippings) (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Día de los Muertos, 1959-2004, undated; (5 folders; see also: Altars; Aguilar, Laura; Carrasco, Barbara; California; Gamboa, Diane; Garcia, Margaret; Guerrera-Cruz, Dolores; Guerrero, Zarco; Venegas, Sybil; Box 30) (Box 9, Folder 16-20)
    (handwritten letter to Sister Karen from TYF, 08/20/1977 [draft]; exhibition and event announcements and invitations; clippings; brochures; TYF's typed notes, "Altares y Offrendas"; TYF's handwritten notes on "Dia de los Muertos"; Roberto Chavez post cards; flyers; photograph of altar; "Ritual and El Dia de Los Muertos: A Day of the Dead Curriculum Handbook for Teachers" prepared by the Education Department of the Mexican Museum; catalog; excerpt from Las Ofrenda: The Days of the Dead, monologues of artists on fax to TYF; invitation; exhibition announcement; photocopy of article by TYF, "Recuerdo, Descubrimiento, Voluntad: Mexican/Chicano Customs for the Day of the Dead"; catalog; TYF's notes on Dia de los Muertes; color photocopy of altar; The Mexican Notebook: The Newsletter of the Consulate of Mexico in New York, vol. 6 no. 9, November 1997)
  - Diaz, Alejandro (see also: Blue Star Art Space; Zamudia-Taylor, Victor), 1996-2003 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    (exhibition announcement and curatorial statement; ArtPace International Artist-In-Residence Program brochure; "I [heart] Cuba" essay by Victor Zamudio Taylor; note to TYF from Diaz, 01/29/2003, with "Brillo/AMOR" edition for MoMAQNS [cardboard box, collapsed])
  - Díaz, Michael, Performance Artist, 1988, undated (Box 9, Folder 22)
    (letter to TYF from Díaz, 03/19/1988, and postcard, undated)
  - Dominguez, Benjamin, Painter, circa 1993; (catalog) (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Dominguez, Eddie, 1999; (clipping) (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Doolin, Kaleta (see: La Junta de los Ríos) (Box 9)
  - Los Dos Streetscapers, Collaborative Group (see also: Healy, Wayne), 1978, 1982; (clippings) (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Dumont, Roberto Z. (see also: Border Culture), 1985 (Box 9, Folder 26)